# **AMRESH KUMAR THAKUR**

# **Linux & Cloud Operation**

Sr. Analyst 3 Infrastructure Services (DXC Technology)

+917820809624

Amreshkumar785@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/amreshkumar785

#### **CARRIER OBJECTIVE**

Seeking challenging middle position in Unix Administration and Cloud Operation with technology driven organization of high repute where I can apply my innovative ideas and help the organization in achieving excellence in service and quality. A diligent and dedicated system administrator with over 3 years 4 months of industries experience.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- > Good hands-on Experience on Red hat Enterprise Linux Based Workstation.
- > OS kernel Patching of RHEL, VXVM Upgrade and oracle DB patching.
- > Hands on Experience in AWS & Ansible Tower.
- > AWS IAM Management, VPC, S3 Storage & Deployment of EC2 machine.
- > Good Understanding of Terraform.
- Virtualization Technology ( VSphere, VCentre & Vmotion)
- Working on Maestro & Hermes Tools.
- > TCP, N/W Wireshark.
- Logical Volume Manager
- > BMC Helix, HP OMI & ServiceNow Tools.

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- Bash scripting & TSM Backup
- Good Knowledge on VCS Veritas Cluster
- Good Knowledge on Oracle DB patching.
- > Knowledge on CI/CD Pipeline Jenkin.
- > Strong troubleshooting skills
- > Ability to handle multiple tasks and work independently as well as in a team.
- > RAID configuration.
- > Network File System (NFS) Administration and local YUM Repository configuration.
- Good Knowledge on Virtualization Technology.
- > Working on ticketing tool like BMC Helix and monitoring tools like HP OMI.
- > Handling second level escalation problem tickets.

# **Sound Working Knowledge on Linux Administration**

- ➤ Good hands-on Knowledge on Red hat Enterprise Linux Version 6/7/8.
- > Troubleshooting Hardware and Operating system related issue of Severs.
- > Servers Configuration, OS kernel patching, installation/uninstallation.
- Creating of Logical Volume Manager.
- Creating, modifying users, changing permissions, setting sticky/attribute bit and ownership of files and directory.
- File-system Administration and Additional Storage (partition, making file System, mounting, permissions, ACL,swap).
- > Decommissioning, managing the server remotely via SSH.
- Locking, Deleting & Password resetting for LinuxAccount.
- Package management via RPM and YUM, apt-get installs.
- Network Management by using nmcli, Wireshark utility.
- Scheduling Jobs by using at and Cron.
- Managing Security by using Firewall and IPtables.
- > Daily Check List about Server Health performance (ps,top,sar,vmstat).
- Password reset using single user mode OR break the rootPassword.
- > Trouble shooting related to Linux security and collector based.
- > Troubleshoot OS related issues via Linux rescue mode and Redhat Support Team by opening Case and follow till the closer.
- Application Deployment with the co-ordination of application and developer Team.

# **Professional Experience**

# **DXC Technology** (Feb 2022 – Present)

Sr. Analyst 3 Infrastructure Services (DXC Technology - Payroll)

Globtier Infotech Private Limited (DXC Technology – Partner Payroll) - (Feb 2022 – May 2023)

Location:- Noida, India

#### **Project Name: WWDC (ST Microelectronic)**

#### **Role Description:**

- Managing 10k severs of RHEL & AIX based Workstations, Servers and Application hosted in Datacenter and AWS & Azure Cloud.
- Servers Configuration, OS kernel patching, installation/uninstallation/ configuration of application packages, VXVM upgrade, Oracle DB patching, LVM using Ansible Tower.
- > Veritas Cluster & Vmotion of servers in our datacenter.
- Working on Helix Ticket such as incident, WO, RCA & CR.
- > Performed daily administrative tasks such as troubleshooting automation.
- > Working on TSM & Net Backup.
- > Troubleshooting of application such IBM maestro and Hermes application.
- > General system administration, including OS level maintenance, along with basic application support and standard operating.

#### **PREVIOUS COMPANY**

# **GVR Technolabs Private Limited (Bharat Electronic Limited)**

TSE (Linux Admin), Oct 2020 - Feb 2022

# **Project Name: IACCS (Indian Air Command and Control System-Airforce)**

#### **Description:**

- Monitoring real time track data in RtiAdminConsole, Network monitoring, sniffing tools like Wireshark and patching of servers, OC & Workstation.
- Configuration and update blade server, Rack Server process systems, auxiliary devices, and peripheral equipment
- > Automation with bash and python scripting
- > Troubleshooting the automation of installing and configuring applications in the test, OA & Production environment
- > Make Changes in Scripting of Various Modules for client requirement from Zenwork satellite server.

#### **Strengths**

- > Self-Starter & Keen to Learn New Technologies.
- > Self-Motivator, Quick Lerner.
- ➤ Working in a 24/7 environment with an efficient team to meet the SLA (Service Level Agreement) with the client.

#### **Education**

### S S College of Engineering, Udaipur (Rajasthan Technical University, Kota)

B.Tech (Computer science & Engineering)

75.32 % with Honors Degree - 2015-2019

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name: Amresh Kumar Thakur Father Name: Arjun Thakur Date of Birth: 23/03/1997 Marital Status: Unmarried

Languages Known: English, Hindi

Permanent Address: Harpur Belwa Vaishali, Bihar 844126 Corresponding address: Sector 12 Noida UP 201301

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Amresh Kumar Thakur